we need to determine
what the code we've been given will
print
on lines one through five we have a
method definition
for the method count sheep
within that method we invoke the integer
times method
and for each iteration we print
something to the screen
on line seven we are invoking the count
sheet method
and outputting the return value of that
method
so when thinking about what this code
will output
we need to be aware that we are printing
something to the screen
on line three from within the count
sheep method
as well as printing the return value of
count sheep to the screen
when we invoke it on line seven
to understand what this code will print
we need to understand the integer times
method
we call times on an integer in this case
5 and ruby will iterate through the
given block
integer number of times so in this case
five times the block parameter
which in this case we've named sheep
will represent each number of this count
however it's important to note that the
count begins at zero
so the last number in the count will
actually be one
less than the integer on which we called
times
in this particular case we can expect
that times will count from zero
to four knowing that we can expect that
our call to put s on line
three will output zero one
two three four for now
let's invoke count sheep without the
call to put us
outputting its return value and just see
the output that comes from within the
method
itself
as expected we've printed out zero
one two three four as
our call to the times method iterated
through our block
five times
now that we understand what is output
from within the count sheet method
we need to know what the return value of
this method will be
to determine what the call to put s on
line 7 will output
it may seem a little confusing to
determine
what the evaluated result of the last
line of this method
is however
remember that this do end block that we
see on lines
two through four is actually an
argument we're passing to the times
method
the last line being executed in this
count sheet method
is our invocation of the times method
so to determine the return value of the
count sheet method
we need to know the return value of the
times method
and if we didn't already know this we
could check out the ruby documentation
for the integer times method and we
would see
that times returns the integer it was
called on
in this case that's five so we can
expect that the count sheet method will
return the integer
five
let's run our code again and we'll
expect to see
both the output from within the method
counting from 0 to
4 and the output of the return value of
this method
which we expect to be five
and we see the expected result
if this isn't clear enough we can
comment out the call to put us
within the count sheet method and just
output the return value of count sheep
and you can see that it's five